The date has changed. It's the 23rd.
日期变了 来到了23日
Ms. Nagumo. I found some new shampoo.
老师 有新的洗发水
Oh. Thanks.
好 谢谢
Ms. Nagumo.
老师
Shinpei and I saw the memory from 14 years ago with you and Heine.
我和慎平看到了14年前的记忆 就是老师与波稻相遇时
Right. I heard.
嗯 我听说了
At that time, you were...
老师那个时候…
Really flat! Can I touch and see what they're like now?
明明是平胸啊 可以给我摸摸吗
Fine by me.
我不介意
They do.
痛的
Why did Heine end up like that?
波稻为什么会变成那样
She was a normal little girl... when she was playing with you.
和老师玩的时候 看起来就是个 普通的可爱女孩子
That's right. I was a fool to have let my curiosity get the best of me.
是啊 是我太愚蠢了 我不该出于好奇心就与她扯上关系
I think this body of mine was born from a part of Heine.
我认为我的身体是从波稻身上来的
A piece of Heine that fell when Ryunosuke was killed... that was me.
龙之介先生被杀时 从波稻身上 崩出来的那个就是我
I'm afraid that...
我很害怕
I might turn out like Heine someday.
害怕有一天我也会像波稻那样 变得疯狂起来
Don't worry. I'll kill you if you do.
放心吧 到时候我会杀了你的
Mio.
泠
What? Oh, it's me.
什么啊 原来是我
What is it?
有什么事
You're so cold.
这么冷淡
Well, I guess that makes sense. I do hate myself.
也是 毕竟我最讨厌自己了
What are you saying?
你想说什么
Tiny nose, short fingers, too much hair, too sweaty.
塌塌的鼻梁 短短的手指 毛发浓密 又爱出汗
Stop.
别说了
You hate it all.
我全都很讨厌
Everything's the complete opposite of Sis.
因为全都和姐姐的相反
It's not just the way you look, but your grades and personality too...
不只是外表 成绩也是 性格也是
I said stop!
叫你别说了
You're the shadow... of Sis.
你才是姐姐的影子
How long are you going to keep it in? At least tell Shinpei how you feel.
你打算忍耐到什么时候 至少把自己的心意告诉小慎吧
I'll tell him if you won't.
再这么磨磨蹭蹭的
These are your mother's ashes.
这是你母亲的骨灰
I would never feed Heine the woman I loved.
我怎么可能让波稻吃掉她
She died on January 3, 2013 from heart failure.
她的忌日是2013年1月3日 死因为心力衰竭
So you lied about the donor.
你说找到捐赠者的事是骗人的吗
She was already dead on the day of her surgery.
妈妈做手术那天就已经死了吧
You should have told me such an important thing.
这么重要的事 为什么不说
The Hishigata family has been involved with shadows for 300 years.
菱形家300年来都与影子有牵连
This secret must be passed down,
这个秘密也必须有人继承下去
but I only needed one successor.
但后继者只能有一个
My father told this only to me, and not my brothers.
我的父亲也只告诉了我 没有告诉我的哥哥和弟弟
I thought it would be too much for you.
我觉得这对你来说负担太大了
You believe that human life is precious, don't you, Sou?
窗 你把人的生命看得很重吧？
Of course, I do!
这不是理所当然的吗
That's why I couldn't tell you.
所以我才觉得你不行
I'm sorry.
对不起
If you want to apologize to someone, apologize to Tokiko.
道歉的话 去对朱鹭子说吧
Somehow, I can't really blame Dr. Hishigata.
为什么呢 我并不是特别觉得 菱形医生是错的
He just did everything he could to save someone he loved.
他只是为了救重要的人 所以才会不择手段
I'm not sure I wouldn't do the same if I were in his position.
如果站在他的立场上 我没有自信自己不会做出同样的事
But the fact remains that
但是从结果上来说 我们就是
Human sacrifices were made into shadows, and the memories of their murders erased.
牺牲的人们变成了影子 被杀的记忆就会消失
He thought no one would find out.
没人会知道这件事
It seems like your father planned further ahead.
在你爸爸的计划中 还有后续吧
Yes.
是的
They're shadows, but Ushioh is Ushio.
就算是影子 潮就是潮啊
Your mother Chitoseh is Chitose too.
千登势阿姨也是千登势阿姨 我果然没有自信啊
You're too kind.
你真是个好人
Shinpei.
慎平哥
When was the last time you slept?
你最后一次睡觉是什么时候
What?
什么
Through your many loops, you've been continuously awake.
你循环了这么多次 意识一直是连续的吧？
You have horrible bags under your eyes.
黑眼圈很重哦
It's true that I've been awake the whole time.
还真是 我可能一直都是醒着的
Don't wear yourself out.
好了 太勉强自己可不行哦
Thanks.
嗯
We're all with you, so get some rest tonight.
大家都在 今晚就好好睡一觉吧
She's right, it might be my only chance to sleep.
朱鹭子说得没错 现在也许是唯一能睡的时机了
Thanks.
谢谢
Where are you going?
你要去哪
Oh, it's you, Ushioh.
是你啊 潮
Don't act alone. I told you to tell me if you need to go to the bathroom.
单独行动很危险的 不是说了 去厕所也要打声招呼吗
Let me go home.
让我回去一趟吧
Go home alone? No way. What are you thinking...
回家？你一个人？不行 你在想什…
Did you forget something?
是忘了什么东西吗
Well, something like that. Can I go?
算是吧 无论如何也不行吗
I don't know...
也不是 我想想
Why don't I come with you, if you really need to go home?
那我和你一起去吧 如果你一定要回去的话
I'll be right back. Wait outside.
我很快回来 你在外面等吧
Why do you just walk in like that?
你怎么也这么随意地进来了
Well, I felt the presence of a shadow.
因为我感觉到了影子的气息
Don't worry. It can't move.
不用担心 那家伙动不了
I'm home.
我回来了
Is this person...
这个人该不会是…
Yeah, it's a shadow. Of my wife.
嗯 是影子 我老伴的
Two months ago, she went to the farm and came back a shadow.
正好是两个月前 她一个人去田里 回来的时候已经变成影子了
The moment I saw that light, I thought of that day.
被她用那个光照的时候 我很快就回想起来
I remembered the day Ryunosuke was killed, 14 years ago.
14年前那一天龙之介被杀的情景
It tried to copy me, but I had immunity.
这家伙当时是想复制我 但我有免疫了
What...
什…
What's wrong?
怎么回事
It's acting strange. It never did that before.
不太对劲 她还是第一次这样
She probably received the same telepathy from Heine that made Chitose go mad.
你太太应该也和千登势阿姨一样 接收到了波稻的心灵感应
Is that so?
这样啊…
Wait, Nezu!
根津先生 等一下
Sorry, but let us be.
抱歉 让我们两个人单独相处一下吧
Wait! I can hack into her, and she'll be herself again!
等等 只要我入侵就让她恢复 变回你原来的太太
Even if you do, it's still a shadow, and it's unlike you or Mrs. Hishigata.
就算恢复了 这家伙也还是影子 而且和你或菱形太太不同
It killed my wife and took her form. It's my wife's enemy.
这家伙是杀了我老伴后变身的 是我老伴的仇人
But...
可是…
I couldn't kill it until now.
我一直没能杀了她
I wanted to exterminate shadows, yet let my greatest enemy live.
嘴上说着要驱除影子 却让我最大的仇人活到现在
I don't need any more extra time.
我不再需要与老伴额外相处的时间了
Just let me end this to have closure.
拜托了 让我也做个了断吧
Please.
拜托了
I'm so sorry, Kaoru. I'll be with you soon.
对不起 薰 我很快就会去陪你了
Impressive, Miss Negoro. Your bandaging is perfect.
不愧是根来护士 伤口处理得很完美
The long night ended.
漫长的夜晚结束了
It's morning.
到早上了
Are you okay? You really slept a lot.
喂 真的没问题吗 还真的熟睡了一晚上
CURRENT LIMIT
现在 界限
Good, the approaching edge of time is now a bit farther.
太好了 不断靠近的时间边缘线变远了
I now have a little leeway to the number of loops left.
这样一来 剩下的循环次数 就稍微充裕了一些
But my eyes still hurt and my headache is getting worse.
不过眼睛深处的疼痛感没有消失 头痛也越来越剧烈了
Is everyone safe?
大家都还安全吗
Right!
对了
Good morning.
早上好
We all made it to the morning of the 23rd alive.
所有人都平安迎来了23日的早晨
Today, the 23rd, we will be hunting.
今天23日将会是狩猎的日子
Before the final battle tomorrow, we must weaken the shadows' forces.
为了明天的决战做准备 要尽量削弱影子的战力
Our first target are the shadows Ms. Nagumo saw at the funeral.
首要目标是南云老师在葬礼上 发现的影子
Ms. Nagumo's team will go to the Kogaitos, while Ushioh's team, the Hitobuchis.
南云队负责调查子垣内家 而我们潮队负责调查人人渕家
Our team first went back to Bistro Kofune.
在那之前潮队先回了一趟小舟餐厅
Alain was prepping for lunch hours.
艾伦正在做开店的准备
We thought he would be angry, but he kindly welcomed us home.
本以为他会生气 但艾伦只是 温和地说了声“你们回来啦”
Rose and Gil watched Kofune all night, so we sent them back to Tokiko.
帮忙看守了小舟家一整晚的 罗森和吉尔也回到朱鹭子那边了
Mio will help Alain. Shadow Mio stands guard. Sou stays too.
泠帮艾伦 影子泠留下来保护她 窗也留在小舟家这里吧
So Sis and Shinpei will be all alone today.
那今天姐姐和小慎就是独处了
What? Ah, yes.
什么 嗯 是啊
Sounds nice... huh, Mio?
真好啊 对吧 泠？
What?
什么
It's fine. We have Sou with us.
我们这边有窗在 没事的
Stay safe, Sis and Shinpei.
姐姐和小慎都要小心
Here, use this.
-还有这个拿去用吧 -什么
It's real hair from Sis.
姐姐的头发是本人的
What's this for?
什么意思
Oh, I get it!
对了
I found hair on the floor of some rooms. It's got her data, right?
我把掉落在卫生间和房间里的 收集起来了 头发也有姐姐的数据吧
I only found a few strands, but you can use them to recover.
虽然只有几根 但应该也能当成恢复药来用吧
Mio, you're a genius!
泠 你真是个天才
My hair has been restored!
头发复活
All right, let's do this.
好 那我们走吧
Yeah.
嗯
Sou, take care of Mio.
窗 泠就拜托你了
Leave it to me. Don't die out there.
交给我吧 你们也千万别死
Shinpei.
小慎
I have to tell you something later...
稍后我有话想和你说
so you have to come back in one piece.
所以你一定要平安回来
Got it. Call me if anything happens.
知道了 有事就马上联系我们
Yeah.
嗯
I don't sense any shadows nearby. They're not here anymore.
附近没有气息 已经不在这家里面了
Just like Ms. Nagumo said, the Hitobuchi family has been wiped out.
南云老师说得没错 人渕一家都被杀了
She saw the shadow of Kanae Hitobuchi, a school teacher nicknamed "Bucchi."
南云老师在葬礼上发现的影子
She taught every kid on the island, including Ushio, Ms. Nagumo, and me.
当然 我 潮 南云老师 以及岛上的孩子都被她教过
There she is. Hey, look!
来了 喂 快来看
Her hair is blonde.
那家伙是金发
She's got blue eyes too.
眼睛也是蓝色的
-Creepy! -She's a foreigner!
好恶心
-You foreigner!
外国人
-Hey, foreigner! -Hey!
-外国人 -喂
Die!
去死吧
U-Ushio...
潮
You're not getting away!
别跑
Hey! What are you doing?
喂 你们在干什么啊
Bucchi.
阿渕
It's not my fault. I didn't do anything wrong.
又不是我的错 我没错
No, you didn't do anything wrong.
是啊 不是潮的错
You were just upset.
你只是不甘心吧
I'm not upset.
没有不甘心
Those two bully weak kids because they're weak.
那些家伙就知道欺负弱者 因为他们很弱
But I'm not a weak kid. I just taught them that.
但是我不弱 我只是告诉他们而已
You certainly are strong...
潮的确很强
but violence is unacceptable.
但是使用暴力是不对的
People who are truly strong don't hurt others.
真正强大的人不会去伤害任何人
What does that mean? I don't get it.
老师在说什么啊 我听不懂
These hands of yours are not made to hurt people.
老师希望你的手不要用来伤害别人
I want you to use them to hold hands and to hug.
而是用来握住他人的手 抚摸他人 拥抱他人
You want me to hold hands with them? Eww, no way!
要我握他们的手？我才不要 好恶心
Shinpei.
慎平
Ah, yes.
是
Keep a good eye on Ushio. I'm counting on you.
以后你要负责看好潮哦 靠你了
Next time, think about what I said before you make a fist.
下一次想挥拳之前 要试着思考一下
I can't promise that. I'll punch back if someone punches me.
这我可答应不了 被欺负就该还手
Okay.
嗯
You're so honest. I love that about you.
老师最喜欢潮的坦率了
Bucchi. She was so kind.
阿渕是个好老师啊
I know.
是啊
But she was scary when she got mad.
不过生起气来也挺可怕的
Yeah.
嗯
We're the only ones who can avenge her death.
能给老师报仇的就只有我们了
We followed the presence of shadows into the forest of Mount Takanosu.
我们循着影子的气息 朝着鹰巢山的森林深处走去
Well? Feel anything?
怎么样 有反应吗
Yes, I feel them more.
嗯 越来越强烈了
Be cautious. They probably sense me too.
小心点 对方应该也觉察到我的存在了
Yes, I know.
嗯 我知道
Shinpei, are you nervous?
慎平 你该不会是在紧张吧
Of course, I am. It's just the two of us against them.
当然了 我们只有两个人
Don't worry, I got your back. You just step back and relax...
有我在没事啦 慎平就像平常一样 俯瞰一下 冷静下来
Shinpei, get on.
慎平 上来
G-Go away!
别过来 别过来啊
You've got so much energy as always, Hamaji.
很有精神嘛 浜路
You'll be a tasty meal.
应该会是很可口的食物
What? Ushio?
潮？
I missed one! Shinpei! Behind the kids!
漏杀了一个 慎平 孩子们的身后
You got so big, Shinpei. Are you doing well?
你长大了啊 慎平 过得好吗
Yes... Mrs. Hitobuchi.
我很好 人渕老师
So good shadows are fighting bad ones, and you're a good shadow.
那个 也就是说坏影子和好影子战斗 潮是好影子
Correct answer, Todai!
没错 灯台 回答正确
No worries. We'll beat up all the bad shadows.
放心吧 我们会把坏影子全部打败的
Right, Shinpei...
对吧 慎平…
Exactly!
说得没错
Why are you still up there?
你要在上面待到什么时候
I can't get down! You put me here!
我下不来 不是你把我送到这上面来的吗
Shinpei really gets led around by the nose.
慎平是妻管严呀
Yeah! They're like a couple.
嗯 好像夫妻哦
-It's not like that!
-才不是
Listen, this is a secret mission, so you can't tell any grown-ups.
听好了 这可是绝密任务 不可以跟大人说哦
Roger that!
明白
This is so cool!
好厉害的感觉
I couldn't tell the kids that the real Bucchi was killed.
真正的阿渕已经被杀了 这句话我还是没能说出口
That's for the best. There's no need to scare them.
这样就好 也不会吓到他们
Will they keep quiet about the shadows?
那些孩子会对影子的事保密吗
It's okay. No one would believe them anyway.
没事的 就算说了也没人信
Shinpei, there's blood. It's still fresh.
慎平 有血 还很新
Did Bucchi do this?
是阿渕的影子干的吗
It's a 34-year-old woman who's not from the island.
34岁 女性 不是这岛上的人
She lives in Osaka. She's a tourist.
住在大阪 是来这里玩的游客
I don't see a human stain. That tourist was taken away.
没有人形的痕迹 那名游客是被搬过来的
Darn it, Heine is eating more to heal wounds from yesterday.
可恶 波稻为了治疗昨天的伤 吃的人比平时多了
What a fool. Eating more strangers won't heal her.
愚蠢 无论吃多少人都治不好的
For both Shiori Kobayakawa and Heine, originals no longer exist.
小早川诗织和波稻 他们的原型都不在这世上了
Ushioh?
潮？
Wait, did I just say something?
奇怪 我刚才是不是说了什么
Hold on.
等一下
It's Ms. Nagumo.
南云老师打来的
Let's meet up with everyone like we planned.
先按计划和大家会合吧
I'll have the kids go to Kofune. It's safest there.
让他们待在餐厅小舟 那样是最安全的
Both teams met up and reported on the situation.
两支队伍集合 互相报告状况
Basically, we only defeated the shadows of Mrs. Hitobuchi and two kids.
从结论上来说 我们干掉了 人渕老师和两个孩子的影子
The Kogaito home had human stains, but no shadows were present.
子垣内家只留下了人形的痕迹 还没能发现影子
Totsumura, along with us, then checked the shadows we fought in the gym.
之后以凸村先生为主导 带着我们
All of their homes were empty,
每一家都搬空了
but the families told neighbors that they were leaving.
所有人都告诉了周围人 自己要去旅行或出差后才消失的
For instance,
比如说小早川家
I called the relatives, but there was no truth to that.
已经向那对夫妇确认过了 根本没这回事
In the first loop, your shadow said that they were running from debt.
第一轮的时候 影子凸村说的是 小早川家因为逃债跑路了
Debt?
逃债？
Are they trying to avoid suspicion in case we erased them?
他们是提前做了准备 就算被我们 驱除和消灭也不会引起骚乱吗
They must want the summer festival to go on as planned tomorrow.
是为了让明天的夏日庆典顺利举行吧
It doesn't seem like they're going to attack us.
对方似乎不打算主动出击
Are they afraid of Ushioh's hacking?
也许是害怕潮姐姐的入侵吧
They might not show their backs to us anymore.
那些家伙打算把狐狸尾巴藏起来了
So they want the festival to happen. Can't we cancel it somehow?
那些家伙最担心的是庆典中止吗 有没有办法能中止庆典啊
To do that, we'll need to see that man.
那就只能去见见那个人了
Looking back, I was trying to meet him right from the start.
回想起来 我从一开始 就想去见那个人了
It's the first place where I was killed.
我最初被杀的地方
Hiruko. It's where everything began.
蛭子大人 这里就是一切的开端
Hello.
你好
Oh, hello.
是你啊 你好
I wanted to talk to you, Mr. Karikiri. Do you have time?
我有些话想对雁切先生你说 你有时间吗
Of course. Why don't we talk inside? Come with me.
嗯 当然没问题 别站着了 进来说吧